Finding Aid for Lawrence L. Witt and Laura A. Edge papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lawrence L. Witt and Laura A. Edge papers 1943-2012, 1943-1946
Edge, Laura A.
30.9 GB online
1.5 linear feet (in 2 boxes)
2014014 Aa 2
Lawrence L. Witt was a Detroit native who served in the Army Air Force during World War II and was a prisoner of war (POW) for eleven months after getting shot down over Nazi Germany. His daughter Laura A. Edge later researched her father's story and wrote a book about his and other airmen's experiences as prisoners of war in WWII. Correspondence, various documents relating to military and prisoner of war experience, and audio-visual materials including oral histories of several WWII veterans.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Laura A. Edge (donor 11053 ) in 2014.
The collection is open to research.
Born June 1, 1923 in Detroit, Lawrence Lee Witt served in the U.S. Army Air Force during World War II. On May 12, 1944, he was shot down over Nazi Germany. He was a prisoner of war for the next eleven months, primarily at the Stalag Luft IV prison camp, located in what is now eastern Poland.
Prior to enlisting in the army, Witt worked for the Ford Motor Company, and he enjoyed a long career there after the war as well. He attended the Ford Training School as a teenager and served as an apprentice before enlisting, initially earning a deferment for assisting in research vital to the war effort. Intending to serve as an airplane mechanic, he enlisted in the Army Air Force in December 1942. Due to shifting military needs, however, after training as a mechanic he was sent to gunnery school, and served as the flight engineer and waist gunner on a B-17 with missions over Nazi Germany.
Witt's plane was shot down on May 12, 1944 and he soon became a prisoner of war, along with four of his crewmates (five did not survive being shot down). From late May through early February, he was held at Stalag Luft IV in what is now Poland. In early February, the Nazis evacuated the camp in a forced march of several hundred miles west to Stalag 357. After avoiding yet another forced march, he was liberated by the British on April 16, 1945. Returning to the United States in May, his military service continued, mostly spent receiving treatment for the physical and psychological trauma he endured as a prisoner of war, before being honorably discharged November 1, 1945.
On January 26, 1946, Lawrence Witt married Lois Davis, whom he proposed to while on furlough in July 1945. Together they had three daughters, Laura, Ellen, and Ruth. Laura, intrigued by her father's history, conducted extensive research on her father's and others' war experiences through correspondence, oral history interviews, official military documents, and other sources. She published a book based on her research On the Wings of Dawn: American Airmen as Germany's Prisoners: Their Story of Courage, Sacrifice, and Survival, in 2012.
At nearly 87 years of age, Lawrence L. Witt died on April 10, 2010.
The collection is organized in four series: Correspondence, Collected Materials, Oral Histories, and Audio-Visual materials.
The Lawrence Witt and Laura Edge papers document Witt's experiences during and after World War II, as well as his daughter's research on his and other airmen's experiences as prisoners of war in Nazi Germany. Most series consist of folders (both original and digitized copies) originally ordered and numbered by Laura Edge.
Subjects:
Prisoners of war--Germany--Personal narratives, American.; Soldiers--Michigan--Correspondence.; Stalag Luft IV.; United States. Army Air Forces. Bombardment Group (H), 96th.; Witt, Laurence L.; World War, 1939-1945--Prisoners and prisons, German.
Genre Terms:
Digital audio formats.; Digital images.; Digital moving image formats.; Interviews.
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series (1 linear foot and 12.0 GB, 1943-2012) includes both original and digitized versions of documents and is divided into three subseries: Family correspondence, Personal correspondence, and Research correspondence. Family correspondence contains letters and related materials sent or received by Lawrence Witt's mother, Gladys Collins. The bulk of the correspondence was sent by Witt himself, and much of that from when he was a prisoner of war (POW) in Germany. Also included are notifications sent by the Department of War about Witt's status, a few notes or letters to Witt, and related materials such as newspaper clippings. Personal correspondence primarily consists of letters sent between Lawrence Witt and his future wife, Lois Davis, but also includes a few letters from other friends and acquaintances. The bulk of this subseries was sent following the end of the war. The Research correspondence subseries contains letters related to Laura Edge's research on her father's and other airmen's experiences as prisoners of war in Germany during World War II.
  - Family correspondence 1943-1945
    - Digitized family correspondence, .PDF file and .ZIP file
    - Transcriptions of V-Mail and Kreigsdefangen Posts from Witt to Collins (Box 1)
    - 1-Witt to Collins (Utah), circa December 1943 (Box 1)
    - 2-Witt to Collins (Nebraska) April 5, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 3-Witt to Collins (England) V-Mail April 15, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 4-Witt to Collins (England) V-Mail April 18, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 5-Witt to Collins (England) V-Mail April 2, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 6-Witt to Collins (England) V-Mail April 27, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 7-Witt to Collins (England) V-Mail April 28, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 8-Witt to Collins (England) V-Mail April 29, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 9-Witt to Collins (England) V-Mail May 2, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 10-Collins to Witt (Imlay City) Birthday Card May 3, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 11-Witt to Collins (England) V-Mail May 10, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 12-Witt to Collins (England) V-Mail May 11, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 13-Secretary of War to Collins MIA Telegram May 26, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 14-War Department Letter May 26, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 15-News clipping, circa June 1944 (Box 1)
    - 16-Witt to Collins (Germany) May 1944 (Box 1)
    - 17-Witt to Collins (Germany) June 1944 (Box 1)
    - 18-Witt to Collins (Germany) June 15, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 19-Witt to Collins (Germany) June 18, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 20-War Department Telegram July 5, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 21-Newspaper Clipping July 9, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 22-Witt to Collins (Germany) circa June or July 1944 (Box 1)
    - 23-Witt to Collins (Germany) July 4, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 24-Witt to Collins (Germany) July 13, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 25-Witt to Collins (Germany) July 13, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 26-Witt to Collins (Germany) Kriegsgefangenenlager July 29, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 27-Witt to Collins (Germany) August 3, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 28-MacMannis to Mrs. Witt August 5, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 29-Witt to Collins (Germany) undated, postmarked December 1944 (Box 1)
    - 30-Witt to Collins (Germany) August 9, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 31-Witt to Collins (Germany), undated postmarked January 1945 (Box 1)
    - 32-Witt to Collins (Germany) October 4, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 33-Witt to Collins (Germany) undated, postmarked February 1945 (Box 1)
    - 34-Witt to Collins (Germany) November 9, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 35-Witt to Collins April 23, 1945 (Box 1)
    - 36-Witt to Collins (Brussels) April 27, 1944 (Box 1)
    - 37-Edith to Collins (Montana) Telegram May 10, 1945 (Box 1)
    - 38-War Department Telegram May 14, 1945 (Box 1)
    - 39-Witt to Collins Telegram 1945 (Box 1)
    - 40-War Department Telegram May 17, 1945 (Box 1)
    - 41-Witt to Collins (New York) Telegram May 24, 1945 (Box 1)
    - 42-Newspaper clipping: "Imlay Soldier Loses 30 LBS" circa May 1945 (Box 1)
    - 43-Newspaper Clipping: "Captured After Jump From Plane" circa May 1945 (Box 1)
    - Western Union Telegram envelopes (Box 1)
  - Personal correspondence 1943-1946, 1990, 2001
    - Digitized personal correspondence, .PDF file and .ZIP files
      (Includes all material listed under Manuscript personal correspondence)
    - Manuscript personal correspondence
      - 001-Witt's Index to letters (Box 1)
      - 002-Davis to Witt January 7, 1943 (Box 1)
      - 003-Davis to Witt February 27, 1943 (Box 1)
      - 004-Davis to Witt March 2, 1943 (Box 1)
      - 005-Witt to Davis April 27, 1943 (Box 1)
      - 006-Witt to Davis December 8, 1943 (Box 1)
      - 007-Witt to Davis March 1, 1944 (Box 1)
      - 008-Witt to Davis May 4, 1944 (Box 1)
      - 009-Witt to Davis December 5, 1944 (Box 1)
      - 010-Witt to Davis May 3, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 011-Witt to Davis May 26, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 012-Witt to Davis August 1, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 013-Witt to Davis August 3, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 014-Witt to Davis August 4, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 015-Davis to Witt August 5, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 016-Witt to Davis August 5, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 017-Witt to Davis August 7, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 018-Davis to Witt August 7, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 019-Davis to Witt August 8, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 020-Witt to Davis August 8, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 021-Davis to Witt August 9, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 022-Witt to Davis August 9, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 023-Davis to Witt August 10, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 024-Witt to Davis August 10, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 025-Witt to Davis August 14, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 026-Davis to Witt August 12, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 027-Witt to Davis August 12, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 028-Witt to Davis August 13, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 029-Davis to Witt August 13, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 030-Davis to Witt August 14, 1945 & August 15, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 031-Witt to Davis August 14, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 032-Witt to Davis August 15, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 033-Witt to Davis August 16, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 034-Witt to Davis August 17, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 035-Witt to Davis August 17, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 036-Davis to Witt August 18, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 037-Witt to Davis August 18, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 038-Davis to Witt August 16, 1945, August 17, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 039-Davis to Witt August 19, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 040-Witt to Davis August 19, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 041-Davis to Witt August 20, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 042-Witt to Davis August 20, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 043-Davis to Witt August 21, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 044-Witt to Davis August 21, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 045-Witt to Davis August 21, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 046-Davis to Witt August 22, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 047-Witt to Davis August 22, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 048-Davis to Witt August 23, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 049-Witt to Davis August 24, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 050-Davis to Witt August 24, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 051-Witt to Davis August 25, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 052-Davis to Witt August 25, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 053-Witt to Davis August 26, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 054-Davis to Witt August 26, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 055-Davis to Witt August 27, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 056-Davis to Witt August 28, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 057-Witt to Davis August 28, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 058-Witt to Davis August 29, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 059-Davis to Witt August 30, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 060-Davis to Witt August 29, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 061-Witt to Davis August 30, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 062-Davis to Witt August 31, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 063-Witt to Davis August 31, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 064-Davis to Witt September 1, 1945, September 2, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 065-Witt to Davis September 2, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 066-Davis to Witt September 3, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 067-Witt to Davis September 3, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 068-Davis to Witt September 4, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 069-Witt to Davis September 4, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 070-Davis to Witt September 5, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 071-Witt to Davis September 6, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 072-Davis to Witt September 6, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 073-Witt to Davis September 7, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 074-Davis to Witt September 8, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 075-Witt to Davis September 8, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 076-Witt to Davis September 9, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 077-Davis to Witt September 9, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 078-Witt to Davis September 10, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 079-Davis to Witt September 10, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 080-Davis to Witt September 11, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 081-Witt to Davis September 12, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 082-Davis to Witt September 12, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 083-Witt to Davis September 13, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 084-Davis to Witt September 14, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 085-Witt to Davis September 14, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 086-Witt to Davis September 14, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 087-Witt to Davis September 15, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 088-Davis to Witt September 15, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 089-Davis to Witt September 16, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 090-Witt to Davis September 18, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 091-Witt to Davis September 19, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 092-Witt to Davis September 20, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 093-Witt to Davis September 21, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 094-Davis to Witt September 24, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 095-Witt to Davis September 24, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 096-Davis to Witt September 25, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 097-Witt to Davis September 27, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 098-Davis to Witt September 26, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 099-Davis to Witt September 27, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 100-Davis to Witt September 29, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 101-Davis to Witt September 30, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 102-Witt to Davis October 1, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 103-Davis to Witt October 1, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 104-Witt to Davis October 1, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 105-Davis to Witt October 2, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 106-Witt to Davis October 3, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 107-Davis to Witt October 4, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 108-Davis to Witt October 3, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 109-Witt to Davis October 4, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 110-Witt to Davis October 6, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 111-Davis to Witt October 6, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 112-Witt to Davis October 7, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 113-Davis to Witt October 7, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 114-Witt to Davis October 8, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 115-Davis to Witt October 8, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 116-Witt to Davis October 8, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 117-Davis to Witt October 9, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 118-Witt to Davis October 9, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 119-Witt to Davis October 10, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 120-Davis to Witt October 11, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 121-Davis to Witt October 10, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 122-Marguerite Hanley to Lawrence Witt October 10, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 123-Witt to Davis October 12, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 124-Witt to Davis October 11, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 125-Davis to Witt October 12, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 126-Witt to Davis October 13, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 127-Davis to Witt October 13, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 128-Witt to Davis October 14, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 129-Davis to Witt October 14, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 130-Witt to Davis October 15, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 131-Davis to Witt October 15, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 132-Witt to Davis October 16, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 133-Davis to Witt October 16, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 134-Witt to Davis October 17, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 135-Davis to Witt October 17, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 136-Witt to Davis October 18, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 137-Davis to Witt October 18, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 138-Witt to Davis October 19, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 139-Davis to Witt October 19, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 140-Davis to Witt October 20, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 141-Witt to Davis October 21, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 142-Witt to Davis October 21, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 143-Davis to Witt October 21, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 144-Davis to Witt October 22, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 145-Witt to Davis October 23, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 146-Davis to Witt October 24, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 147-Davis to Witt October 23, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 148-Witt to Davis October 25, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 149-Witt to Davis, postmarked October 25, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 150-Davis to Witt October 25, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 151-Witt to Davis October 26, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 152-Davis to Witt October 26, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 153-Witt to Davis October 27, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 154-Davis to Witt October 27, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 155-Witt to Davis October 28, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 156-Davis to Witt October 28, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 157-Witt to Davis October 29, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 158-Davis to Witt October 29, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 159-Witt to Davis October 31, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 160-Witt to Davis October 30, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 161-Witt to Davis October 31, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 162-Donald Ringe to the Witts April 15, 1946 (Box 1)
      - 163-Mary Ringe to Witt October 11, 1945 (Box 1)
      - 164-Fred Andy Anderson to Witt May 5, 1946 (Box 1)
      - 165-James Davis to Witt July 17, 1990 (Box 1)
      - 166-Dewitt Boatright to Witt May 8, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Research correspondence 2003-2012
    - Digitized research correspondence, .PDF file and .ZIP files
      (Includes all material listed under Manuscript research correspondence)
    - Manuscript research correspondence
      - 01-Letters to Laura Edge from Dr Gerhard Kaschuba 2006-2007 (Box 1)
      - 02-Letters to Laura Edge from Joseph P. O'Donnell 2007-2008 (Box 1)
      - 03-Letters to Laura Edge from Alexander Gorashko 2004-2012 (Box 1)
      - 07-Letters to Laura Edge by John Anderson 2003-2012 (Box 1)
      - 08-Letter & Photos to Laura Edge from Sara Jouette (Box 1)
      - 09-Letter to Laura Edge from John Herwig (Box 1)
      - 10-Letters to Laura Edge from Robert F. Kerr (Box 1)
      - 11-Letter to Laura Edge from Wendell Parrish April 13, 2005 (Box 1)
      - 12-Letters to Laura Edge from Heinz Hungerbuhler 2004-2006, 2012, 16 folders (Box 1)
- Collected materials
  The Collected materials series (0.5 linear feet and 14.8 GB, 1943-2010) includes originals, photocopies, and digitized versions of documents and is divided into three subseries: Military documents, Stalag Luft IV documents, and Miscellaneous. The Military documents subseries contains a variety of documents related to Lawrence Witt's military service. These include discharge papers, medical records documenting the physical and psychological implications of Witt's war experiences, certificates and diplomas, and other documents as well as copies of official military records that Edge requested as research materials. The Stalag Luft IV documents subseries consists of diagrams, notes, photographs, and printed materials related to the Stalag Luft IV prisoner of war camp. The Miscellaneous subseries includes the transcript of a serviceman John Anderson's diary, Witt's life story used at his funeral, and notes from interviews of Witt's crewmates.
  - Military documents 1943-1955, 1989, 2000-2010, undated
    - Digitized folders 1-13 1943-2010, .PDF file and .ZIP files
      (Includes all material listed under Manuscript folders 1-13)
    - Manuscript folders 1-13 1943-2010
      - 01-L. Witt's handwritten notes on dates of events from documents and letters (Box 2)
      - 02-L. Witt Life Insurance Papers 1943-1944 (Box 2)
      - 03-Diploma from Army Air Force Technical School 1943 (Box 2)
      - 04-Flight Records and Individual Record of Combat Missions 1943-1944 (Box 2)
      - 05-List of combat crew members January 11, 1944 (Box 2)
      - 06-VA Disability Papers 2006-2010 (Box 2)
      - 07-Discharge and separation papers 1945 (Box 2)
      - 08-Disability Awards 1947, 1951 (Box 2)
      - 09-Army Air Force Certificate of Appreciation circa 1945 (Box 2)
      - 10-Mission Intelligence Report for 12 May 1944 June 1944, photocopy (Box 2)
      - 11-Summary of Operations May 12, 1944, photocopy (Box 2)
      - 12-Lead Bombardier's Report May 12, 1944, photocopy (Box 2)
      - 13-Missing Aircrew Report 5359, photocopy and microfiche (Box 2)
    - Individual Deceased Personnel Files (IDPF)
      - 14-IDFP for Harold Tucker, photocopy; .PDF file and .ZIP file (Box 2)
      - 15-IDPF for Robert Greenwood, (photocopy); .PDF file and .ZIP file (Box 2)
      - 16-IDPF for Walter Slemensky, photocopy; .PDF file and .ZIP file (Box 2)
      - 17-IDPF for Samuel Detwiler, photocopy; .PDF file and .ZIP file (Box 2)
      - 18-IDPF for Jennings Greuter, photocopy; .PDF file and .ZIP file (Box 2)
    - Digitized Folders 19-27 1944-2010, .PDF file and .ZIP files
      (Includes all material listed under Manuscript Folders 19-27)
    - Manuscript Folders 19-27 1944-2010
      - 19-Harold Tucker's Grave at Arlington National Cemetery, map and photographs undated (Box 2)
      - 20-Lavern Maisak Kriegsgefangenen card 1944 (Box 2)
      - 21-Lawrence Witt memoranda and verification of Purple Heart and POW Medals undated, 1989 (Box 2)
      - 22-Lawrence Witt Award of Disability January 11, 1947 (Box 2)
      - 23-L Witt VA Health Records 1945-1949 (Box 2)
      - 24-L Witt VA Health Records 1953-1955 (Box 2)
      - 25-Lawrence Witt's Death Certificate 2010 (Box 2)
      - 26-96th Bomb Group Memorial Pamphlet 1983 (Box 2)
      - 27-Certificates of Appreciation 2000, circa 2010 (Box 2)
  - Stalag Luft IV documents 1944-1945, 1984, 1991, 2004, undated
    - Digitized Stalag Luft IV documents, .PDF file and .ZIP files
      (Includes all folders listed under Manuscript Stalag Luft IV documents)
    - Manuscript Stalag Luft IV documents
      - 01-L Witt's drawing of Stalag Luft IV (Box 2)
      - 02-Men in Lager B, Barrack 2, Room 1 (Box 2)
      - 03-Report of Protecting Power June 29, 1944 (Box 2)
      - 04-Report of the International Red Cross October 5, 1944 (Box 2)
      - 05-Report of the Protecting Power October 10, 1944 (Box 2)
      - 06-Stalag Luft IV Photos from Joseph O'Donnell (Box 2)
      - 07-Geroge W. Guderly's Map of Stalag Luft IV (Box 2)
      - 08-Joseph O'Donnell's map of forced March (Box 2)
      - 09-Description of forced March taken by Lloyd Stoller (from diary of Glenn W. Bordner) and note to L. Edge 1945, 2004 (Box 2)
      - 10-Stalag Luft IV May 1944 image and diagram from Joseph O'Donnell, 1991 (Box 2)
      - 11-L. Witt's rendering of "C" Lager (Box 2)
      - 12-Room Assignments in C Lager (Box 2)
      - 13- Barbed Wire Interlude by Robert Ludden (copyright 1945), 1984 (Box 2)
      - 14- Barbed Boredom by Charles Janis (copyright 1950), 1984 (Box 2)
      - 15-List of Stalag Luft IV Prisoners taken to Stalag 357, arrived March 20, 1945, photocopy (Box 2)
      - 16-Stalag 357 map and letter 1992 (Box 2)
      - 17-Letter from Alexander Gorashko to Lawrence Witt regarding Stalag 357 January 20, 2004 (Box 2)
      - 18- Prisoner of War Bulletin, volume 3, number 3, March 1945 (Box 2)
      - 19-Brussels Leave Hostels map and information circa 1945 (Box 2)
      - 20-Sea Tiger Troop Ship reference material undated, photocopies (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous 1945, 2004, 2007, 2010
    - Edge, Laura. "A Day of Infamy for the 96th: 12 May 1944." 96th Bomb Group Newsletter, No. 50, February 2007 (Box 2)
      (not digitized)
    - Digitized Veterans' interviews, stories, and notes, .PDF files and .ZIP file
      (Includes all folders listed under Manuscript Veterans' interviews, stories, and notes)
    - Manuscript Veterans' interviews, stories, and notes
      - 04-Interview of Willis Boatright by Laura Edge July 23, 2004 (Box 2)
      - 05-Interview of Lloyd Stoller by Laura Edge June 16, 2004 (Box 2)
      - 06-Souvenir Book of Walter Lawrence (transcript) 1945 (Box 2)
      - Lawrence Witt Eulogy 2010 (Box 2)
      - World War II diary, John H. Anderson (transcript) (Box 2)
- Audio-Visual materials